'임산부를 위한 출산 준비'
레이첼, 임신하면 손가락이
Did you know that during pregnancy..
두 배로 불어서 예전으로
다시 안 돌아가는 거 알아?
your fingers swell up to twice
their size and never go back?
정말? 이리 줘봐
Oh, my God! Let me see that.
너 매번 속더라
You fall for it every time.
야! 내가 입었던 임신복 가져왔어
Hey! I brought you
my old maternity clothes.
피비, 정말 고마워
와, 너무 귀엽다!
Oh, Pheebs, that's so sweet.
Oh, those are so cute!
이거 봐, 아기가 자라면 이렇게
늘어나고
Look. See how they expand
as the baby grows?
출산 후에는 멜론 훔칠 때
쓰면 돼
And after the baby's born
they're great for shoplifting melons.
잘 됐다, 모두 여기 있네
내일 4시 추수 감사절 파티!
Good, you're all here.
Thanksgiving, 4:00.
내가 누구 초대했게?
고등학교 때 윌 컬버트 생각 나?
Guess who I invited? Remember
Will Culvert from high school?
- 아니
- 로스네 반이었던 애 있잖아
-No.
-He was in Ross' class.
밴드부도 하고, 좀 뚱뚱했던...
아니 무지 뚱뚱해서
Marching band, was kind of overweight.
Really overweight.
내가 비교적 날씬해 보였었어
I was his thin friend.
기억 안나, 혹시 네 상상 속의
남자친구 말하는 거 아냐?
I don't remember. Are you talking
about your imaginary boyfriend?
아니, 걔는 재리드였구
No, that was Jared.
와, 재리드 생각 안한지
무지 오래됐다
Wow. Haven't thought about him
in a long time.
윌이 일 때문에 여기 왔는데
갈 곳이 없데서 내가 초대했어
Will's here on business, and he didn't have
a place to go, so I invited him here.
- 잘 했네
- 살이 완전히 쭉 빠졌더라구
-That's nice.
-Oh, he's lost a bunch of weight.
근사해 보여
실은, 끝내주게 멋있어
He looks good.
Okay, I mean really gorgeous.
- 그래도 난 챈들러 사랑해
- 가끔씩 그 말을 해주길 바래
-I still love Chandler.
-Wouldn't hurt you to say it once in a while.
그리고 올해는 칠면조 요리
안할거야
Just so you know,
I'm not gonna make a turkey this year..
- 뭐?
- 피비가 칠면조를 안 먹잖아
-What?
-Phoebe doesn't eat turkey.
- 피비!
- 칠면조는 아름답고 영리한 동물이야
-Phoebe!
-Turkeys are beautiful, intelligent animals.
아니야! 못생기고 멍청하고
맛있는 동물이야!
No, they're not! They're ugly
and stupid and delicious!
또 칠면조 먹는 건 전통이잖아
Plus, eating them is like a tradition.
인디언이랑 카우보이랑 같이
추수 감사절 보낼 때부터 그랬어
It goes back to the first Thanksgiving when
the lndians sat down with the cowboys.
맞아, 그때 플리머스 바위에서
큰 로데오를 했었지
Oh, right. That's when they had
that big rodeo at Plymouth Rock.
윌도 아직 다이어트 중이고
챈들러도 추수 감사절 음식은 안 먹어
It's not just Phoebe. Will's still on a diet,
Chandler doesn't eat Thanksgiving food..
- 레이첼도 닭 종류는 피하고 있잖아
- 정말이야?
-Rachel's having her aversion to poultry.
-She is?
응, 전날 너 치킨 먹고 있을 때
내가 자리 피했잖아
Yeah. Remember? I had to leave
the other day when you had that chicken.
난 또 내가 치킨을 잡고
I thought that was
because I put the whole thing..
식탁에서 걸음마 시켜서 그런 줄
알았지
on my hand
and made it walk across the table.
세 명 때문에 칠면조 요리를 하기는
너무 번거로워
It's not worth it to make a whole turkey
for just three people. It's a lot of work.
그래도 추수 감사절엔 칠면조야!
But you gotta have turkey
on Thanksgiving!
칠면조 없는 추수 감사절은
애플파이 없는 독립기념일이야
Thanksgiving with no turkey is like
Fourth of July with no apple pie.
또 피자 두 판 없는 금요일
Or Friday with no two pizzas.
좋아, 대신 남기면 안돼
Fine, if it means that much to you.
But there's gonna be a ton left over.
걱정마, 내가 다 해치울게
No. I promise I will finish that turkey.
칠면조 한 마리를
다 먹을 수 있다구?
You're telling me you can eat
almost an entire turkey in one sitting?
당연하지
트리비아니 가문을 믿어!
That's right. Because I'm a Tribbiani!
This is what we do.
우리는 훌륭한 사상가나
지도자 집안도 아니고
We may not be great
thinkers or world leaders..
달리기도 못하지만...
아무튼 먹는 건 잘 해!
we don't read a lot or run fast,
but damn it, we can eat!
프렌즈 시즌 8
'추수감사절 파티'
4개의 와이드 리시버, 3번과 18번
Four wide receivers. On third and 18.
내년엔 아기가 있을 거라는
사실이 이상하지 않아?
Isn't it weird how next year
there will be a baby at the table?
레이첼 아기 말이야
그리고 네 생각도 알겠어
Rachel's. But good to know
where you're at.
- 얘들아!
- 안녕!
-Hey!
- 해피 추수 감사절!
- 너도!
-Happy Thanksgiving.
-You too!
- 도와줄까?
- 응
-Can I help?
-Yes.
보통 챈들러가 도와주는데
지금 한창 TV 보는 중이라
Chandler usually helps,
but he's into the game.
냅킨 좀 접어줄래?
고구마 익었나 보고 올께
Could you fold these napkins? I'm gonna
go across the hall to check on the yams.
어, 그렇게 하지 말고
No, sweetie. No, not like that.
너무 촌스럽잖아
We're not at a barn dance.
백조 모양으로 접어, 크리스마스 때
내가 가르쳐 준 거 기억 나?
Fold them like swans.
I showed you at Christmas. Remember?
네가 막 소리지르던 거 기억 난다
Yeah, it all just came
screaming back to me.
- 재밌어?
- 몰라
-So how's the game?
-I have no idea.
- 뭐?
- 그냥 보는 척 하는 거야
-What?
-I'm pretending to watch..
그럼 안 도와줘도 되니까
so I don't have to help out.
어쩜 그럴 수가 있어!
너 정말 영리하다!
I don't believe you!
That is brilliant!
- 모니카는 몰라?
- 몰라
-And Monica has no idea?
-No.
가끔씩 TV에 대고
소리도 질러야 해
Once in a while,
I just yell stuff at the TV.
헤이! 잘한다!
Hey! What? Aw! Hey!
- 너희 팀이 이기는 중이야?
- 앤더슨이 방금 득점했어
-Your team winning?
-Anderson just scored again.
앤더슨이라는 선수는 없어
There is no Anderson.
나도 이거 해야지... 모니카?
I wanna get in on this. Hey, Mon?
못 도와주겠어
나도 이 경기 정말 보고 싶거든
I can't help you after all.
I didn't realize this game was on.
- 축구 좋아했어?
- 평소에는 아닌데...
-You like football?
-Normally, I don't.
지금 그린 베이팀이 하잖아
But, you know, Green Bay is playing.
- 그린 베이 팬이야?
- 내가 유일하게 좋아하는 베이잖아
-You like Green Bay?
-It's only my favorite bay.
- 해피 추수 감사절!
- 윌, 와줘서 정말 고마워
-Happy Thanksgiving.
-Will, I'm so glad that you came.
정말 멋지다, 얼마나 뺀 거야?
You look great. You must've lost..
68킬로, 서브웨이 샌드위치
광고에 나갈 거야
150 pounds. I'll be on one of those
Subway commercials.
- 파이네!
- 무지방, 무설탕, 무버터
-A pie!
-It's no fat, no sugar, no dairy.
- 맛없어, 그냥 버려
- 친구들 소개할게
-It's no good. Throw it out.
-Meet some people.
내 남편 챈들러
이쪽은 윌이야
This is my husband, Chandler.
This is Will.
안녕하세요, 제가 지금 게임에
몰두하고 있어서요
Oh, hey. I'd shake your hand
but I'm really into the game.
게다가 한 자리에 있지 않는 것이
제 자아에도 도움이 될 것 같네요
Plus, it'd be better for my ego
if we didn't stand next to each other.
- 여기는 피비
- 안녕
-This is Phoebe.
-Hi.
와우!
Hey. Wow!
잘 했어
Well done.
- 나 좀 도와줄래?
- 그래, 너 정말 예쁘다
-Wanna give me a hand?
-I can't get over how great you look.
- 너도, 몸매가 끝내준다
- 게임 보는 거지, 귀먹은 게 아니야
-You look incredible too. You're so fit.
-I'm watching the game, but I'm not deaf.
- 참, 로스도 올 거야
- 잘 됐다, 로스 보고 싶었는데
-I meant to tell you, Ross is coming.
-Great, I love Ross.
그리고 레이첼 그린도 와
Good. And Rachel Greene too.
- 왜? 무슨 일 있어?
- 아니야, 괜찮아
-Is there a problem?
-No. It's okay.
그냥... 정말 걔가 싫었어
It's just.. God, I hated her.
- 뭐?
- 내가 정말 싫어했어
-What?
-I hated her.
고등학교 때 나한테
아주 못되게 굴었거든
She was horrible to me in high school.
하지만 다 지난 일이니까
지금 보면 재미있을 지도 모르지
But hey, that was a long time ago. I'm in
a good place. Might be fun to see her again.
케이크나 쿠키 같은 거 없어?
Got any cakes or cookies
or something?
안돼, 윌! 그러지마!
No, Will! No!
소리 한 번 질러야 하지 않을까?
It's been a while since we screamed.
Maybe we should.
- 좋아
- 얼른
-Oh, okay. No!
-Come on!
이 망할! 지옥에나 가라!
Damn you, ref! You burn in hell!
뭐 하는 거야?
칠면조 한 마리 다 먹어야지
What are you doing?
You've got an entire turkey to eat.
인체가 어떻게 작동하는지
모르는구나
Let me explain to you how
the human body works.
먼저 위를 워밍업 해줘야 해
I have to warm up my stomach first.
- 이건 스트레칭 같은 거지
- 좋아
-Eating chips is like stretching.
-Okay.
- 걱정마, 난 절대 배 안부르니까
- 내가 그 맘을 알지
-Don't worry, Tribbianis never get full.
-I'm here to tell you something.
아무리 먹어도 그 공허감이
채워지지 않는 거야
You can eat and eat, but nothing
will ever fill that void.
- 이 친구는 도대체 누구야?
- 고등학교 친구 윌이야, 이쪽은 조이
-Who the hell is this guy?
-This is Will, from high school. This is Joey.
- 감자칩 먹을래요?
- 아뇨
-Want some chips?
-No.
- 윌!
- 로스!
-Will!
-Ross!
야, 반갑다!
너 정말 멋지다! 섹시한 걸
Hey, you came!
Man, you look incredible! Hot stuff!
- 섹시한 걸?
- 만나서 반갑다
-Hot stuff?
-It's good to see you, man.
그러게, 무슨 일로 온 거야?
Yeah. You too. So, what are you up to?
- 공산품 중개인으로 일하거든
- 굉장한 직업 같은데
-I'm a commodities broker.
-That sounds interesting.
- 응, 그렇지 않아
- 어?
-Yeah, it's not.
-Oh.
- 하지만 부자고 날씬하지
- 오오!
-But I'm rich and thin.
-Oh.
랜스 데이비스 졸업 파티 이후로
못 만난 거 같다
I haven't seen you since
Lance Davis' graduation party.
그날 정말 재밌었지
That was such a fun night.
우리도 갔으면 좋았을 걸
그래도 재밌었어
Would've been good if we had
gotten in, but still fun.
그땐 참 순진했지
공룡 좋아했던 거 기억나?
We were lame. Do you remember
how into dinosaurs we were?
- 응
- 지금 무슨 일해?
-Yeah.
-So, what do you do now?
여기 얼마나 있다 가는 거야?
So how long are you in town?
- 안녕
- 고마워
-Hi.
-Hey, sweetie. Oh, good.
레이첼 그린
Rachel Greene.
아 참, 너 괜찮겠어?
Oh, that's right.
Are you gonna be okay?
괜찮아, 단지...
쟤가 싫을 뿐이야, 정말 싫어!
Oh, I'll be fine. It's just..
God, I hate her, Ross! I hate her!
다 옛날 일이잖아
High school was a long time ago.
고구마 들고 서 있는 거 봐
Look at her standing there
with those yams.
나의 최대의 적!
레이첼 그린과 탄수화물
My two greatest enemies: Rachel Greene
and complex carbohydrates.
세상에나, 저 사람 누구야?
Oh, my God. Who is that?
- 윌이야, 우리 고등학교 동창
- 난 잘 모르겠는데
-That's Will, from high school.
-Oh! I do not remember him.
와, 정말 섹시함이 몸에서
배어난다
Wow, really got that sexy
smoldering thing going on.
어쩜 좋아, 날 쳐다보고 있어
Oh, my God. Look at the way
he's just staring at me.
나한테 뭔가 말하는 거 같은데
He's trying to mouth something to me.
난 네가 싫어!
I hate you!
- 자, 저녁 준비 다 됐어요!
- 오케이!
-Okay, dinner's ready!
-Okay!
- 대단해, 대단해
- 누가 이겼어?
-Solid effort. Solid effort.
-Oh, so who won?
- 그린 베이
- 디트로이트
-Green Bay.
-Detroit.
- 뭐?
- 기술상 라이온스가 이겼어
-What?
-The Lions technically won.
하지만 도덕적으로는
그린 베이가 이긴 거야
But it was a moral victory
for the Green Bay Mermen.
안녕! 윌 맞지?
난 레이첼 그린이야
Hi! Will, right?
Right, hi. I'm Rachel Greene.
- 아, 기억하고 있지
- 정말? 고맙기도 해라
-Oh, I remember you.
-Really? Aren't you sweet?
난 솔직히 잘 기억이 안나
I gotta tell you, I'm having
the hardest time placing you.
잠깐만! 알 거 같아
Hang on! I think I remember you.
랜스 데이비스 졸업 파티에서
우리 둘이 좀 놀지 않았니?
Did we fool around at
Lance Davis' graduation party?
- 정말 대단하다
- 고마워
-You are unbelievable.
-Thank you.
레이첼? 여기 앉을래?
윌은 저쪽에 앉아
Rachel? Why don't you sit here?
And Will, you sit way over there.
겨우 그거야?
충분히 혼자 해치울 수 있어
That's it? Even if nobody helps me,
I can eat that. No problem.
- 나한테 맡겨 놔
- 이건 챈들러꺼, 치킨이야
-At least give me a challenge.
-This is Chandler's chicken.
이게 칠면조고
This is the turkey.
와, 몇 킬로짜리야?
Oh. How big is that?
- 8킬로
- 나 태어났을 때랑 같네
-About 19 pounds.
-It's like me when I was born.
- 고구마 먹을 사람? 윌?
- 너 그거 즐기는 거지, 그렇지?
-Who would like some yams? Will?
-You'd like that, wouldn't you?
뭐? 누가 치킨하고
What? Oh, can we please keep
the chicken..
칠면조 좀 저쪽으로 치워줄래?
and the turkey on the other side?
- 냄새가 너무...
- 너답다
-The smell is just..
-Typical.
- 뭐라구?
- 너답다구
-What?
-I said it was typical.
레이첼 여왕께서는 레이첼 랜드에서
뭐든지 원하는 대로 하지
Typical of you. Queen Rachel does
whatever she wants in Rachel-land.
정말 이 남자 누구니?
Seriously, who is this guy?
미안한데, 나한테 유감 있어?
Sorry, do you have a problem with me?
- 잘 모르겠는데, 그럴까? 응?
- 그런 거 같은데
-I don't know. Do I? Do I?
-I think you do.
고등학교 때 네가
좀 못되게 굴었어
You were a little mean
to him in high school.
- 좀? 내 인생을 망친 장본인이야
- 기억이 안 나, 미안해
-A little mean? You made my life miserable.
-I had no idea. I'm sorry.
당연히 미안해야지
고구마 좀 줘
Well, you should be.
Screw it. Bring on the yams.
다이어트 중이잖아
But you worked so hard.
- 고구마!
- 알았어
-Yams!
-Okay.
고등학교 때 내가 뭘 했던
정말 미안해
I'm real sorry for whatever
I did to you in high school.
나 혼자만이 아니었어, 클럽도 있었거든
It wasn't just me. We had a club.
- 클럽이라구?
- "레이첼 그린이 싫어" 클럽!
-You had a club?
-The "I Hate Rachel Greene Club"!
클럽을 만들어서
나를 미워했단 말이야?
So you all just joined together
to hate me?
- 클럽에 누가 또 있었는데?
- 나하고 로스
-Who else was in this club?
-Me and Ross.
내가 누군지 아니까
지적 안해줘도 돼
No need to point.
She knows who Ross is.
- 너도 그 클럽 회원이었어?
- 그랬다니까
-You were in an "I Hate Rachel" club?
-Yes, he was.
아니야
No, no.
- 또 누가 있었어?
- 태국에서 온 교환학생
-So who else was in this club?
-That exchange student from Thailand.
걔는 뭘 모르고
들어왔던 거 같아
But I don't think he knew what it was.
멋지다
You guys were cool.
나랑 2년간 사귀면서
So, Ross, we went out for two years..
그 클럽 회원이었단
말을 안한 거야?
and you never told me you were
in an "I Hate Rachel Club"?
쟤랑 사귀었어? 우리 규칙은 어쩌구
You went out with her? We had a pact.
- 영구적인 규칙은 아니었잖아
- "영원히"라고 되어 있었어
-It's not like it was binding forever.
-It had the word "eternity" in it.
난 "칠면조가 싫어 클럽"에
가입할까 봐
I'm thinking of joining
an "I Hate Turkey Club."
하지만 난 칠면조 클럽 좋아해
Although, I do love a turkey club.
모니카? 너도 알고 있었어?
Monica? Did you know about this?
아냐, 그래서 둘이 방문을
잠그고 있었던 거야?
I didn't. Is that why
you used to lock the bedroom door?
- 그렇지
- 좀 안심이 된다
-Yeah.
-A little relieved, I gotta say.
레이첼, 미안해
내가 정말 바보 같았어
Look, Rach, I'm sorry, okay?
I was a stupid kid, okay?
- 내가 가입한 이유는...
- 공동 창립
-The only reason I joined..
-Cofounded.
공동 창립...
Cofounded.
공동 창립한 이유는
너를 사랑했기 때문이야
Cofounded the club,
was that I was in love with you.
잘못은 했지만, 잘 생각해 보면
"레이첼이 싫어" 클럽은
I didn't handle it very well. If you think
about it, the "I Hate Rachel Club"..
실제로 "레이첼을 사랑해"
클럽이야
was really
the "I Love Rachel Club."
진짜로 "레이첼이 싫어"
클럽이었단 점만 빼면 그렇지
Except that it was really
the "I Hate Rachel Club."
그래서 모여서 나에 대해
욕한 거야?
So you'd get together
and say mean things about me?
- 그거 보다는 조금 더 했지
- 아냐, 아냐
-We did a little more than that.
-No, no, no.
또 무슨 짓을 했는데?
What else did you do?
- 소문을 퍼뜨렸어
- 무슨 소문?
-We started a rumor.
-What rumor?
그냥 시원하게 뱉어요
Come on, Will,
just take off your shirt and tell us.
- 로스?
- 별거 아니야
-Ross?
-It was no big deal.
그 소문이... 뭐냐면...
We said that.. The rumor was that..
네가 여자와 남자 생식기를
모두 가지고 있다고...
you had both male and female
reproductive parts.
- 뭐야?
- 맞아, 그래서 네 부모님이
-What?
-That's right. We said your parents..
딸로 기르기로 결정했지만
아직도 남자의 흔적이 있다고
flipped a coin, decided to raise you
as a girl, but you still had a hint of a penis.
- 세상에, 이럴 수가!
- 너희가 퍼뜨린 거야?
-Oh, my God!
-You started that?
- 너도 들었어?
- 학교 애들은 다 알걸!
-You heard that?
-Everyone at our school heard it!
우리 학교 애들도 다 알아
네가 그 자웅 동체 치어리더였어?
Everyone at my school heard it.
You were the hermaphrodite cheerleader?
아니야!
Oh, no!
이제 알겠다, 아담 카터가
왜 나랑 데이트 안 했는지
It makes sense now. This is why
Adam Carter wouldn't go out with me.
빌리가 왜 이 부분에서만
머물렀는지
Why Billy would just stay
in this region.
빌리는 지금 게이니까
그건 우리 잘못이 아니지
Billy's gay now, so that one's
not really our fault.
- 왜 나한테 말 안했어?
- 진짜일 수도 있다고 생각했거든
-Why didn't you tell me?
-I thought it might be true.
네가 울면서 나한테 보여줄까봐
너무 무서웠어
I was afraid that you were gonna cry
and then show it to me.
그만 쳐다봐! 아무것도 없어!
거짓말이라구!
Stop staring! There's nothing there!
It's not true!
증거가 필요해
I'm afraid I'm gonna need proof.
얼른 꺼내 봐
Come on, whip it out.
네가 나의 에베레스트 산이다
You are my Everest.
- 다 안 먹어도 돼
- 아니, 이건 나에 대한 도전이야
-You don't have to finish.
-I do. Otherwise, what's next?
오늘 칠면조를 못 끝내면
내일은 초코바 반만 먹고
Today I can't finish a turkey,
but tomorrow I eat half a PowerBar..
나머지는 냉장고에 넣어 두라구?
절대 안되지!
wrap it up and put it
in the fridge? No!
바지 갈아 입어야겠다
도대체 청바지를 왜 입은 거야
I gotta change my pants. What was
I thinking? Jeans have no give.
치우는 거 좀 도와줘
Guys, help me with the dishes.
There's a lot of pots and pans.
도와주고 싶은데 두 번째
경기가 이제 막 시작해서
Honey, I'd love to,
but the second game is about to start.
맞다, 두 번째 게임이 있지
축구여 영원하라
Oh, yeah, the second game.
More football for the Pheebster.
- 어느 팀 경기야?
- 로스엔젤레스
-Who's playing?
-Los Angeles.
내가 알기로는 LA에
축구팀이 없는데
Last time I checked,
Los Angeles didn't have a football team.
내가 LA라고 했어? 내 말은
예전에 LA에 있었던 팀이라구
Did I say Los Angeles? I meant the team
that used to be in Los Angeles..
지금은 세인트 루이스에 있어
내가 아는 것도 있네
and is now in St. Louis.
I actually knew that.
좋아, 그 팀 선수 세 명만 대봐
Okay, quick, name three players
on that team.
그레츠키...
Gretzky..
애거시...
Agassi..
난 예쁜 여자 아이야
I'm a pretty little girl.
숀 맥마혼이 내 졸업앨범에
뭐라고 썼는지 봐
Listen to what Sean McMahon
wrote in my yearbook senior year.
"레이첼, 넌 대단한 사람이야"
소녀가 아니라 "사람"이라구
"Dear Rach, you're such a great
person." Not girl, "person."
내 생각엔 너무 과잉반응
하는 거 같아
I think you're reading a little
too much into it.
"넌 정말 대단한 사람이야,
그 작은 거는 정말 안됐다"
"You're a great person.
Sorry about your teeny weenie."
어쩌길 바래?
What do you want me to do..
전체 학생들에게 전화해서
사실이 아니었다고 말해?
call everyone in the entire school
and tell them it wasn't true?
- 응
- 나 살 빠졌다는 말도 해줘
-Yes.
-Also, tell them I'm skinny now.
나도!
Oh! Me too!
전화 안 할거야
너무 오래된 이야기라구
I won't call anybody.
It was a million years ago.
상관없어, 사람들한테
내가 반반이라고 소문냈잖아!
I don't care. You told people
that I was half and half!
난 고등학교 때 너한테 한 번도
나쁜 짓 한 적 없어
I never did anything to hurt you
in high school.
그건 좀 거짓말이지
That's not totally true.
- 뭐라구?
-What?
네가 그 소문 퍼뜨렸잖아
You did start that rumor about Ross..
로스가 50살 된
도서관 사서랑 잤다구
making out with Mrs. Altmann,
our 50-year-old librarian.
너 그거 어떻게 알았어?
How did you know that?
- 사실이었어?
- 아니
-It's true?
-No.
사실이야, 둘이서
책장 뒤로 가는 거 봤어
Yes, it is. I saw you guys going at it
behind the card catalog.
- 도대체 도서관에서 뭘 한거야?
- 잡지가 있잖아
-Hey, what were you doing in the library?
-They had magazines.
그 아줌마는 타타카키켁이
Mrs. Altmann? She also made out..
태국으로 돌아가기 전에
그 애하고도 잤어
with Ta-Taka-Ki-Kek the night
before he went back to Thailand.
고등학생이 50살된
노인이랑 잤다구?
In high school you made out
with a 50-year-old woman?
- 이봐, 50살처럼 안 보였어!
- 그럼 16살처럼 보였어?
-Hey, she didn't look 50!
-Did she look 16?
졸업 앨범에 그 아줌마
사진도 있어
There's a picture of her
in the yearbook actually.
- 이런!
- 사진 잘 안받는 얼굴이야!
-Wow.
-She didn't photograph well!
사진이 뭔지 잘 몰랐을 거야
She probably wasn't familiar
with the process..
유화 모델로만 서 봐서...
having spent most of her life sitting
for oil paintings.
어쩌다 그랬어? 저녁 먹자고
너를 꼬시든?
How did this happen? Did she lure
you to an early-bird dinner?
하루는 늦게까지 도서관에서
일하는데, 우리 둘만 있었거든
I was working late in the library
one afternoon. It was just the two of us.
낱말 맞추기를 좀
도와 달라고 하더라구
She needed some help
with her word jumble.
그렇게 해서 어쩌다 보니...
And one thing led to another.
그 분은 정말 점잖고 부드러웠어
If you must know,
Anita was very gentle and tender.
고이 잠드소서
May she rest in peace.
- 그 사람 지팡이 짚지 않았니?
- 습한 날에만 그랬어!
-Didn't she walk with a cane?
-Only when it was damp!
그 이야기를 사방에 퍼뜨렸다니...
모두가 안단 말이야?
I can't believe you told people
about this. Everybody knew?
- 나 그 클럽에 다시 가입할거야!
- 예에!
-You know what? I'm back in the club!
-Yeah!
- 회의를 소집할까?
- 모두 모였어?
-Shall I call the meeting to order?
-Is everybody present?
다타카만 빼고
With the exception of Ta-Taka.
- 나도 가입할래!
- 피비!
-I wanna join!
-Phoebe?
미안, 클럽에 가입한 적이 없어서
고등학교를 안갔거든
I'm sorry, but I never got to be in a club.
I didn't go to high school.
그래도 쓰레기통 뒤에 모여서
프랑스어 공부했어
But three of us would meet behind
a dumpster to learn French.
좋아, 그 바보 같은 클럽 계속 해
Fine, you can have
your stupid, little club.
하지만 네가 한 짓이
내가 한 짓보다 훨씬 심한 거야
But what you did to me is way worse
than what I did to you.
- 나한테 반반이라고 했잖아
- 예에!
-You gave me a teeny weenie.
-Yeah!
바보 같은 소리하지 마
레이첼, 그런 소문이 있었어도
You're just being silly.
Rachel, even with that rumor..
넌 가장 인기가 많았잖아
모두다 너처럼 되고 싶어했어
you were one of the most popular girls.
Everyone wanted to be like you.
어떤 애는 너처럼 되려고
바지 속에 막대 사탕도 넣었어
One girl wanted to be like you so much,
she stuffed her pants with a Tootsie Roll.
세상에
Wow.
그리고 오빠, 그 소문 아니었으면
아무도 오빠를 몰랐을 거야
And Ross, if it weren't for her rumor,
no one would've known who you were.
- 덕분에 유명해진 거라구
- 노인과의 로맨스로
-She put you on the map.
-As a romancer of the elderly.
그 부인도 예쁜 얼굴이었어
Mrs. Altmann, you can tell,
she used to be pretty.
눈이 정말 초롱초롱 빛났어
The eyes did still sparkle.
다 옛날 일이야
그 뒤로 많은 일들을 거쳐 왔잖아
This stuff is so way in the past.
You've been through so much since then.
그거 말고도 소중한 일들이
아주 많았잖아
You got so much more
important stuff going on in your life.
그냥 흘려버리면 안돼?
Can't you just let this go?
- 맞아
- 우린 이제 아이도 낳을 거잖아
-She's right.
-We are having a baby together.
잠깐만
Hold on.
- 임신시켰어?
- 응
-You got her pregnant?
-Yeah.
- 결혼할 거야?
- 아니
-Are you getting married?
-No.
임신시키고 결혼은 안한다?
친구!
So you knocked her up but you're
not gonna marry her. Dude.
- 누구 할 사람?
- 좋아
-Anybody?
-Okay.
내가 상상했던 그대로야
It's exactly how I imagined
it would be.
그 칠면조 어디 갔어?
All right, where's that turkey?
- 그거 내 임신복이잖아!
- 아니, 내 추수 감사절 바지야!
-Those are my maternity pants!
-No, these are my Thanksgiving pants!
드디어 다 해치웠다
Well, that's it. I'm done.
땀이 아니라 육수가 흐르네
Here come the meat sweats.
조이, 정말 자랑스럽다
Well, Joey, we're all
very proud of you.
대통령한테 축하전화 올거야
I believe we can expect a call
from the president any moment now.
- 우리가 뭐 도와줄까?
- 내 배만 누르지마
-Anything we can do?
-No. Just nobody press on my stomach.
그 바지는 너 가져
You can keep those pants, by the way.
그거 뭐야?
파이야?
What you got there?
What is that, pie?
- 응, 좀 줄까?
- 아주 조금만 줘봐
-Yeah. You want some?
-Just cut me a little sliver.
좀 더
Little bigger.
아까워서 못 주는 거야?
크게 한 쪽 줘!
Are you afraid you're gonna run out?
Cut me a real piece!